CURRICULUM VITAE

TRINH PHAN-CANH

PhD Student at Medical University of Vienna

Address: Vienna BioCenter, Dr.-Bohr-Gasse 9, 1030 Vienna, Austria

Phone: +43 670 5599 801 - Email: phancanht99@univie.ac.at - Website: phancanhtrinh.com

I have been studying clinical fungal infections for 4 years in Vietnam before starting research in fungal pathogenesis and drug-resistance mechanisms in Vienna. My PhD project focuses on *Candida auris*, an emerging human fungal pathogen causing invasive infections in immunosuppressed patients with a high rate of pan-antifungal drug resistance. In addition to proteomics data, we have evidence that morphogenetic changes play a critical role in *C. auris* pathogenesis, during host-fungal interplay and antifungal drug stress. We hypothesize that phenotypic switching controls virulence traits to promote host colonization, immune evasion, and drug resistance in *Candida auris*. I apply integrated omics datasets (RNA-seq, ATAC-seq, proteomics, metabolomics) and tools of reverse genetics (targeted gene disruption, insertions of reporter genes) to (i) dissect dynamics of regulatory networks and chromatin alterations in morphogenetic switching, host-fungal interaction, and drug response; (ii) identify virulence factors and antifungal drug resistance genes. The long-term goal is discovering the major mechanisms of virulence and drug resistance of *C. auris* to develop better therapeutic strategies.

EDUCATION

1/2021 - Current	PhD in Immunology
	Medical University of Vienna
	Project: Candida auris: virulence factors, morphogenesis and drug resistance of a sticky human fungal
	pathogen. Supervisor: Karl Kuchler
9/2017 - 9/2019	Master's Degree of Pharmacy (Field: Pharmaceutical technology and Pharmaceutics)
	University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City
	GPA: 8.39/10, Thesis: 9.95/10, Ranking: 1/30
11/2015-2/2018	Bachelor of Information Technology (Distance education)
	Vietnam National University - Ho Chi Minh City, University of Information Technology (VNU-HCM, UIT)
	GPA: 8.14/10, Certificate of Excellent awarded by Dean of VNU-HCM, UIT
9/2010-9/2015	University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City
	Degree of Pharmacy, GPA: 7.36/10, Thesis: 10/10

WORKING AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

3/2016-1/2021

Researcher and Lecturer

Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City

- Teaching Microbiology, Molecular biology, and Pharmaceutical biotechnology for pharmacy students. Designing 4 laboratory courses for exchange students from Japan (2019), Korea (2018 and 2019), and Thailand (2019). Participating development of 9 e-learning courses of Microbiology and Parasitology Department. Constructing "Research skill course" (in 3 days) for pharmacy students at UMP from 2016 to 2020 (~70 students every year)
- Research: doing research in antimicrobial drug screening from herbs, lichen, Actinobacteria,
 Myxobacteria, and epidemiology of Gram-negative bacteria and fungal infection
- Management of Mycology Laboratory, Department of Microbiology and Parasitology
- Supervising pharmacy students to conduct diploma thesis and undergraduate summer projects in Microbiology and Parasitology Department, which obtained 3 prizes in student research competitions hold by the UMP's Youth Union and the Ho Chi Minh City Youth Union

5/2019-12/2020

Academic Affairs Specialist (Concurrent position)

Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City

- Administration of E-learning Platform
- Involving in Educational Innovation Team, Course Coordination for Continuing Pharmacy Education, and Quality Assurance Activity of the University

10/2015-1/2017

thongtinthuoc.com.vn - Vietnamese Drug Interactions Checker

Administrating the website, introduce and compile usage manual of the system for healthcare professional, review drug information related to antibiotics and probiotics

COMMUNITY WORK

Founder and coordinator of Seminar series: "PhD Talk", a scientific seminar for Vietnamese students in Austria. https://phdtalk.github.io (2021-present); Member of executive committee of Vietnamese Youth and Student Federation in Europe (2021-present); co-founder and president of Pharmacy Skill Club (2011-2014);

mentor of Pharmacy Academic Club (2017-2021); the secretary of the Youth Union at the Faculty of Pharmacy, UMP; coordinate extracurricular activities of pharmacy students (2500 members; 2019-2021)

HONORS AND AWARDS

2021-2023	Ernst Mach Grant – ASEA-UNINET for a PhD programme in Austria
11/2019	Consolation prize in Eureka Scientific Competition 21 st
	The most reliable and biggest student scientific competition in Vietnam
	Guided a team to conduct a research in extraction and antimicrobial assay of compounds from tropical
	lichen. Trained experimental design, scientific reading, writing, and presentation skill
1/2019	"Damar batu" essential oil: In vitro antimicrobial activities and perspectives
	This seed fund was awarded by Training and Research Academic Collaboration (TRAC) Sweden - Vietnam.
	The TRAC seed funds 2019 granted all students, clinicians and junior scientists to carry out pilot studies
	(collect and/or analyse data) in Vietnam
2015	Homtamin Scholarship
	Awarded by Korea United Pharm Company for outstanding students in academy and social activities
2014	Daewoong Scholarship
	Awarded by Daewoong Pharmaceutical Company for outstanding students in academy
2012	Champion - Scientific Research Contest - Seeking Elixir 3 rd
	Won the champion in the student scientific research titled "Investigating the situation of antibiotic use and
	appropriate antibiotic use solutions in Ho Chi Minh City"

PUBLICATIONS

- Trinh, Phan-Canh*, et al. 2020. "DPPH-scavenging and antimicrobial activities of Asteraceae medicinal plants on uropathogenic bacteria." Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine 2020: 7807026. Citation: 11. (*Corresponding author).
- 2. **Trinh Phan-Canh**, et al.. 2020. "Identification of Acinetobacter baumannii and detection of β lactam antibiotic resistance genes in clinical samples by multiplex PCR." *bioRxiv*.
- 3. **Trinh, Phan Canh** and Duong Thi Thanh Mai. 2019. "Damar Batu essential oil: *In vitro* antimicrobial activities and perspectives." *Research Report to The Training and Research Academic Collaboration (TRAC) Sweden-Vietnam.* https://tinyurl.com/y3qjo3ar.
- 4. **Trinh, Phan Canh**, et al. 2019. "Dirinaria applanata: morphology, chemical composition and antimicrobial activity." Ho Chi Minh City Journal of Medicine 23 (2): 47–54. https://tinyurl.com/y99zn9l7.
- Loc, Nguyen Xuan, et al. and Trinh, Phan Canh *. 2019. "Isolation and screening antimicrobial activity of soil Actinobacteria." Pharmaceutical Journal 59 (524): 45–49. https://tinyurl.com/ya66pr4z. (*Corresponding author).
- 6. Yen, Nguyen Thi Ngoc, **Trinh, Phan Canh**, et al. 2019. "In vitro susceptibility testing of Dermatophytes isolated from Hospital of Dermatovenereology in Ho Chi Minh City to ketoconazole and terbinafine." Ho Chi Minh City Journal of Medicine 23 (3): 55–60. http://tinyurl.com/rqxzg9m. (PCT and NTNY designed research experiments and wrote the manuscript; PCT analysed data and gave discussion).
- 7. Thao, Vu Thanh, **Trinh, Phan Canh**, et al. 2018. "Study on fermentation conditions for *Bacillus subtilis* KP3 spores production." Ho Chi Minh City Journal of Medicine 22 (1): 453–59. https://tinyurl.com/y8uebyma. (PCT and VTT designed research experiments and analysed data; PCT performed experiments).
- 8. Nguyen Huu Dai, Ly Nguyen Hai Du, **Trinh, Phan Canh**, et al. 2020. "Synthesis and Evaluation of Antibacterial and Antifungal Activities of Some Hydrazone Derivatives of Chalcones." Ho Chi Minh City Journal of Medicine 24 (2): 207–11. https://tinyurl.com/yctbfjuc. (PCT designed and performed antimicrobial assay and wrote a part of the manuscript).
- 9. Tran Ngoc Chau, Phung Bich Tuyen, **Trinh, Phan Canh,** et al. 2021. Synthesis and Anti-Staphylococcus aureus activity of 2-pyrazoline and 2-isoxazoline derivatives *Ho Chi Minh City Journal of Medicine* 25 (2): 48 55. https://tinyurl.com/4dmhcs48. (PCT designed and performed antimicrobial assay).

OTHER SKILLS

Basic skill in Python; experimental visualization with Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator; data analysis and visualization with R; Graphpad Prism; excellent in Microsoft Office, Endnote, Window, MacOS

REFERENCE

Karl Kuchler, PhD, Professor in Molecular Biology, Medical University of Vienna **E-Mail:** karl.kuchler@meduniwien.ac.at | Phone: +43 (0)1 4277-61807